what's up everybody phil blackmon with
barbadon.com and today we're going to
cover what happened at the 2021 rogue
invitational but before we get into that
if you want to see any of the coverage
that we had for the rogue invitational
just head over to google type in rogue
invitational barban and all of it is
going to come up on october 29th through
the 31st 2021 40 of the greatest
athletes in the world gathered in austin
texas to take part of the 2021 rogue
invitational the event consisted of
seven events across three days here were
the results for the podiums on the men's
side justin medeiros he wins the event
and the 255 thousand two hundred and
thirteen dollar prize that goes along
with it patrick velner came in second
and jeffrey adler rounded out the podium
for the women it was tia claire toomey
or a five-time fittest woman on earth
takes the win here her third time taking
this title she goes home also with 255
213 dollars in second place the two-time
fittest woman on earth annie thora's
daughter big big showing here for thor
slaughter she walks away with eighty
nine thousand twenty eight dollars and
in third place was gabriella magala
justin medeiros won the title by
finishing no lower than fifth in any of
the seven events this was the first time
he was competing at the invitational and
he bagged the overall win by an 80 point
margin ahead of wellner this was toomey
orr's third rogue invitational title but
it wasn't without serious competition as
thor stoddard stayed on the champions
heels and was even the overall leader
going into the final day of competition
the final event known as the duel was
performed in a bracket tournament format
style where all the competitors
participated in heats each heat
eliminated the slowest times and
advanced the hired performers until the
field was reduced to 5 men and five
women toomey ore barely hung on to the
overall lead against thor's daughter and
the title would come down to whichever
athlete placed better in the final event
thor's daughter struggled with the
sandbag and finished fifth in her heat
as a result she failed to advance to the
finals the final five athletes were
barnhart daniel brandon kristin holta
toomey ohr and laura horvath horvath and
toomey orr moved on to the final two
which clinched the overall victory for
toomey orr she then defeated horbath in
the final showdown the 2021 rogue
invitational promised fans of crossfit a
show and delivered in spades the top
players from the 2021 crossfit game
showed up and showed out on the field
there were also strong performances by
velner thorstadter and more which means
that crossfit isn't a two athlete game
by any means even though right now it
seems to me or and moderos are dominant
it remains to be seen if the individual
athletes from the invitational will be
able to unseat toomey or and maderos
come the 2022 crossfit games but
anything could happen the 2021 rogue
invitational strongman competition is in
the history books and the champion is
2019 world's strongest man martinez
leases lisi's defeated 2021 world's
strongest man champion tom stoltman who
finished in second and the 2020 world's
strongest man alexi novikov who finished
third overall the 2021 rogue
invitational was lisi's first contest
back since the 2020 arnold strongman
classic due to having to recover from
numerous injuries his return to the
report resulted in the best possible
finish here were the final standings in
first place martinez leases with 45
points followed by tom stoltman in
second and alexi novakov in third
leasey's earned the largest prize purse
in the history of the sport a whopping
351 dollars heading into the final event
of competition as is usually the case
with strongman competition involves
stones this was the inverse stone over
hitching post which unlike the atlas
stones the inverse stones are more oddly
shaped as they are not perfect spheres
each man was tasked with lifting the
five stones over a 50 inch high log the
weights were 275 300 365 400 and 420
pounds with a two minute time cap per
single man heat the athlete who lifted
the most stones in the fastest time won
and no tacky was allowed for this event
tom stoltman known as the king of the
stones going into the event but lisi's
is also skilled in the event and
specifically practiced the one motion in
training all he needed to do was play
second or higher and lysis would be the
champion ultimately he was the last to
go lisey's knew exactly the time that he
had to beat and he did he finished all
five stones in 24.45 seconds to take the
overall title tom stoltman also a
blistering time he finished all five
stones in 30.08 seconds and jf caron was
the last man to actually complete all
five stones he performed it in 43.51
seconds leesy's also set a thor hammer
world record in the rogue record
breakers event to cap off an absolutely
incredible weekend so there you have it
that's the 2021 rogue invitational
strongman contest martinez lisey's big
return takes the win stoltman in the
second and novakov in the third i'm phil
blechman for barban.com thanks for
watching
[Music]
you